<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>botswana on fritzvd</title>
    <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/categories/botswana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in botswana on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 10:46:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.fritzvd.com/categories/botswana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vic Falls</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/27/vic-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 10:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/27/vic-falls/</guid>
      <description>Right now I am testing the limits of the slowest connection in the world, as I speedtype this blogpost in existence.
I am writing from Vic Falls in Zimbabwe. A very touristy but nice place. The last few days I have been staying with the aunt and uncle of Washington. Very nice christian people, who took us in the house and helped us on our way.
Yesterday we have arrived safely in Vic Falls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>go siame</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/21/go-siame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 16:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/21/go-siame/</guid>
      <description>After enjoying a lovely Windhoek Special (a nice beer), I felt like updating my blog. First of all, because I haven’t done so for a while. Secondly, because my time in Botswana draws to a close.
The last few days have been busy. Writing, looking at data, finishing a philosophy paper which had a deadline which was a bit more urgent than my thesis.
Today I decided that I could have a bit more of a chill-out-day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>times of refreshing</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/12/times-of-refreshing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 20:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/12/times-of-refreshing/</guid>
      <description>You know how sometimes, life just feels too good to be true? Well, the last few days have been like that. Being finished with my field work made me happy. This meant that I would be in an urban area again. Don’t get me wrong, I love nature. Just being in an urban area means you can have proper coffee again.
So the last few days, I have feasted on vegetables, fruits and other fresh produce withheld from me in Mopipi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ga gona metsi</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/29/ga-gona-metsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 16:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/29/ga-gona-metsi/</guid>
      <description>On a slightly more positive note than the last post, I am doing fine. Really. I actually forgot to write about one of the most significant events of last week.
There was no water (Ga gona metsi). Seriously. This was big mathata (problems). We had to fetch water in barrels, drums, and empty trash bins. Luckily some of my friends here helped me with their skoro-koro (a car that is close to it’s end).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>almost done</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/27/almost-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 11:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/27/almost-done/</guid>
      <description>So this is a bit of an overdue post. But a post nonetheless. I am busy with the final stages of my field work here. And not very mournful about it. My time here has been good, but I’m also up for something different and some people I know and relate with more easily.
Last week I went around to measure the daily use of firewood in this place with a friend of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Okavango le dikwena, dithlare and more</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/15/okavango-le-dikwena-dithlare-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 08:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/15/okavango-le-dikwena-dithlare-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Ok quick recap. I haven’t blogged for about a week and a bit, and a lot more has happened than all my weeks here I think.
So here we go. I’ll try to compress it in small bits.
Last week we had the profs and staff of the Desire project with us to help us, (or rather the other way around). All of us went and picked up cow dung to measure the weight, to get a ‘feel’ of how much an average kraal would produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mopipi</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/04/mopipi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 11:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/04/mopipi/</guid>
      <description>This is now the second week already that I have spent in this place. It is quite an interesting place as you can see from the pictures I’ve uploaded.
Very salty, dry, windy, at times cold and desolate. People are friendly most of the time and I’ve made some friends.
Next week I will be doing something else than household surveys, which is a relief. It is quite boring to go to 140 households and ask the same questions over and over again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lekgoa, lekgoa</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/26/lekgoa-lekgoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 19:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/26/lekgoa-lekgoa/</guid>
      <description>Last Monday I arrived in Mopipi after a 7 hour journey. This is the village I am doing my research in. The house I am staying in is really nice. Mercy, my assistant is renting a room there. The in situ room left a little corner for me. There is a bathroom with running (drinking) water. Even hot water! Mercy has a tv and a fridge (yes, there is electricity). So we have a bit more luxury to retreat to after doing the household surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Botlhale</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/13/botlhale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 10:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/13/botlhale/</guid>
      <description>After being here 3 weeks (today is the start of my fourth week in the South), I thought it’d be good to give another update. This week marks the start of my real ‘field’ research. The previous two weeks of staying in Gaborone were weeks of article reading and enhancing (read: writing anew) my proposal.
Actually I was planning to leave for Mopipi on Monday. However, there are always unexpected changes in this world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ga pula</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/03/ga-pula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 11:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/03/ga-pula/</guid>
      <description>Thursday last I arrived in Gaborone, Botswana after a 7 hour busride through an extraordinary landscape, with shrubs, small trees and yellowish grass as far as the eye can see. A bouquet of dryland vegetation and rock formations passed us by. Beauty is something that is embedded into our wonderful planet earth.
Gaborone or Gabz is quite a new city. Don’t expect old architecture like you see in Windhoek or Cape Town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motoro</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/27/motoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 19:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/27/motoro/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I arrived in South Africa. The first thing I did after going through customs is renting a car. As lekker as it is to have my own mode of transportation, I struggled a bit with driving on the ‘wrong’ side of the road. The first few drives were a bit shaky. After a while I got the hang of it.
The first day I went to Kempton Park to visit a friend of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domela</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/07/domela/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 22:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/07/domela/</guid>
      <description>For those interested, I will conduct a research concerning the use of fuelwood and the feasibility to switch to another, hopefully more renewable energy source. The use of fuelwood puts severe stress on the environment, and can cause further desertification (worsening and growing of a desert)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
