<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Botswana on fritzvd</title>
    <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/categories/botswana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Botswana on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 10:46:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.fritzvd.com/categories/botswana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Vic Falls</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/27/vic-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 10:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/27/vic-falls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now I am testing the limits of the slowest connection in the world, as I speedtype this blogpost in existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing from Vic Falls in Zimbabwe. A very touristy but nice place. The last few days I have been staying with the aunt and uncle of Washington. Very nice christian people, who took us in the house and helped us on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we have arrived safely in Vic Falls. We were hitchhiking from Bulawayo and got a straight lift for 100 ZAR (about 10 EU). Zimbabwe is truely very beautiful. As you drive to Vic Falls lots of different vegetation and soil types appear, that make for a colourful experience. This must be even more exciting in the rainy season, when the grass is not as yellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the looks and talks of it, Zimbabwe is on its way to doing better and better. The shops are full of food, whereas just last December the shops only had toilet paper (so I have been told). There is food, the fuel prices have come down considerably (from 35 ZAR to 10 ZAR) and people are finding ways to make a living other than the criminal paths. You can&amp;#8217;t pay anymore with Zim dollars, but you pay with ZAR and USD. Which works quite well, although your wallet can be a confusing mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What surprises me a bit is the level of education. Far higher than the Batswana do they reach in school and English is understood and spoken by everyone, some better some not so good. Whereas in Botswana the people seldom reach the A-levels, that take you to University, here the people are fairing quite splendidly. My guess is that Zimbabwe will be a platform for development in this region in a future that is not so far as people think it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I will update again, but then from Cape Town (oh yeah, baby!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>go siame</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/21/go-siame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 16:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/21/go-siame/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After enjoying a lovely Windhoek Special (a nice beer), I felt like updating my blog. First of all, because I haven&amp;#8217;t done so for a while. Secondly, because my time in Botswana draws to a close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few days have been busy. Writing, looking at data, finishing a philosophy paper which had a deadline which was a bit more urgent than my thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I decided that I could have a bit more of a chill-out-day. (Last week I was working in the weekend as well! I know, it&amp;#8217;s close to blasphemy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday morning I will be taking a bus to Francistown, where I will cross the border of Botswana for the last time, for now. On the one hand I am very grateful to know that I can conclude a work well done. Yet on the other hand I feel sad to leave a country so beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Botswana is beautiful. The warm reception you will find when meeting people. The blistering sun which competes with gentle, or rough winds. And don&amp;#8217;t forget the lovely beef, tender and juicy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospective I can say that sometimes I have been blind to this beauty. Blinded by frustration and the challenges of being away from home. Home in the deepest sense of the word. Not just the locus of my belongings. Home as a culture I understand and function in well, a language in which I can express myself eloquently and a place where my friends and loved ones are. (On a side note, I have no literal home at the moment: a place to live.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But looking back it is always easier to filter experiences and insights to a picture that may be less real than what was experienced, but nonetheless true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my future permits me, I would certainly not mind to come back to Botswana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for next week, I am planning to go to the Victoria Falls or &lt;em&gt;Mosioathunya &amp;#8211; the smoke that thunders.&lt;/em&gt; I am going to the Zimbabwean side of the Falls, with someone I met in Mopipi: Washington, a nice Zimbabwean, who helped me a lot in Mopipi (and who smokes a lot of pot by the way). Afterwards I will be traveling to Jo&amp;#8217;burg once again and flying of to Cape Town, where I haven&amp;#8217;t been for 3 years. Looking forward to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go siame is Setswana for Goodbye (literally: it&amp;#8217;s alright)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>times of refreshing</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/12/times-of-refreshing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 20:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/08/12/times-of-refreshing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know how sometimes, life just feels too good to be true? Well, the last few days have been like that. Being finished with my field work made me happy. This meant that I would be in an urban area again. Don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong, I love nature. Just being in an urban area means you can have proper coffee again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the last few days, I have feasted on vegetables, fruits and other fresh produce withheld from me in Mopipi. Over the weekend I went to South Africa, to Pretoria for my grandfathers 85th birthday as well as a family reunion day in Potchefstroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides seeing my grandparents, my parents and lots of family members, I went to a normal church again, which was kind of a relief after quite some interesting services in the Mopipi area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I am staying in Gaborone again and am hoping to finish quite a bit of work here before I have to leave the country. As for now, I hope to catch a glimpse of the meteor shower that is about to pass the skies tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. For all NSW people, 31st of July is not my birthday, it is actually 31st of October. &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.technokrat.nl/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ga gona metsi</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/29/ga-gona-metsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 16:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/29/ga-gona-metsi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a slightly more positive note than the last post, I am doing fine. Really. I actually forgot to write about one of the most significant events of last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no water (Ga gona metsi). Seriously. This was big mathata (problems). We had to fetch water in barrels, drums, and empty trash bins. Luckily some of my friends here helped me with their skoro-koro (a car that is close to it&amp;#8217;s end). Lack of water also meant I had to have a luke-warm 6 liter bath the other day, not much of a treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we did we went to a borehole about 500-700 meters away from our house and filled the drums. After sundown, which made it more interesting. Because after sundown, it&amp;#8217;s dark, real dark. I made some pictures but I don&amp;#8217;t have money to upload them now, so I&amp;#8217;ll do that next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now from yesterday we are having problems with the water again. The water is running up to 8.00 or something and then.. nothing. Bizarre world. And a big difference to our normal everyday life in the west.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>almost done</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/27/almost-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 11:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/27/almost-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this is a bit of an overdue post. But a post nonetheless. I am busy with the final stages of my field work here. And not very mournful about it. My time here has been good, but I&amp;#8217;m also up for something different and some people I know and relate with more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I went around to measure the daily use of firewood in this place with a friend of mine. Which has been fun. My friend Moffat and I went from house to house everyday. The people are starting to know me and greet me more freely, which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I spent at someone I know through the church in Gaborone. His name is John Walters. A missionary in Rakops for the last 16 years. Rakops is a village about 60 km from Mopipi. It was fun. He is from England and it was good just to speak some proper English, to enjoy some company with someone who understands Western ways a bit more. Also just to have a weekend of relaxing was nice as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John has the most awesome Land Cruiser in the world. A gift from a Dutch team that came up here. This old Safari truck from the 80&amp;#8217;s. We went around to a Bushmen settlement close to Rakops and did a church service there. The cutest kids, really. And so in need of some love. You can see that most children are not used to play with their parents and thoroughly enjoy it when someone picks them up and swirls them around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week wil be another week of measurements and a presentation at the beginning of next week. After that I&amp;#8217;ll take a bus down to Pretoria where I will be celebrating my grandfathers 85th birthday!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Okavango le dikwena, dithlare and more</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/15/okavango-le-dikwena-dithlare-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 08:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/15/okavango-le-dikwena-dithlare-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok quick recap. I haven&amp;#8217;t blogged for about a week and a bit, and a lot more has happened than all my weeks here I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we go. I&amp;#8217;ll try to compress it in small bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we had the profs and staff of the Desire project with us to help us, (or rather the other way around). All of us went and picked up cow dung to measure the weight, to get a &amp;#8216;feel&amp;#8217; of how much an average kraal would produce. From here on we can make an estimation as to how much biogas an average kraal can produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore we went into the field at different sights, to count trees (ditlhare). Differentiated into species diameter etc. to obtain insight into how much biomass fit for firewood the surrounding of the village has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Than something completely different happened as well. A friend of mine and I had run into each other at the WUR in April and found out that we would in Botswana at the same time, so we made an arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last thursday we met eachother in Maun. This was a small vacation for me. I tagged along with Michiel and Annegina for 5 days. Very relaxed and just lekker to see and talk some Dutch again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went into the Okavango on a boattrip with the three of us and saw crocodiles (dikwena). Lots of them. And big ones! Oh my word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also saw a couple of hippos. But they&amp;#8217;re a bit scary. When they go into the water you can&amp;#8217;t see them. So you have to take some distance with your boat, because they can decide to tip it and snap your back. (hip hip)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close to the place we were staying &amp;#8211; Sepopa &amp;#8211; another fascinating sight was to be spotted: Tsodilo Hills. In a country mostly level with minor hills these small mountains are quite a stunning sight. The indigenous people in this area painted the rocks with paintings of the animals about 2.500 years ago. Quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From today onwards I will be back in Mopipi to continue my work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mopipi</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/04/mopipi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 11:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/07/04/mopipi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is now the second week already that I have spent in this place. It is quite an interesting place as you can see from the pictures I&amp;#8217;ve uploaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very salty, dry, windy, at times cold and desolate. People are friendly most of the time and I&amp;#8217;ve made some friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I will be doing something else than household surveys, which is a relief. It is quite boring to go to 140 households and ask the same questions over and over again. But we are already on 87 of the 140, that is a big relief. Next week I will be measuring the availability of firewood in the area with some people from the University of Botswana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve started a little side project with some locals. We are trying to build a solar cooker out of soda cans. Have to attend these people, so just take a look at the pictures (at the right of this post). And I&amp;#8217;ll update you next week again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lekgoa, lekgoa</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/26/lekgoa-lekgoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 19:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/26/lekgoa-lekgoa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Monday I arrived in Mopipi after a 7 hour journey. This is the village I am doing my research in. The house I am staying in is really nice. Mercy, my assistant is renting a room there. The in situ room left a little corner for me. There is a bathroom with running (drinking) water. Even hot water! Mercy has a tv and a fridge (yes, there is electricity). So we have a bit more luxury to retreat to after doing the household surveys. The days are quite busy and in the evening I have to enter data and every second day make diner as well. And internet is not omni-present, so this update might feel a little late. Sorry for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday we walk through the village to go to several households and ask some questions about their use of firewood. When I walk through the village with my really cool straw hat, the children shout: Lekgoa, lekgoa. The Setswana word for white man. So I shout back at them: black child, black child. No, I don&amp;#8217;t, but that would be funny wouldn&amp;#8217;t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are very friendly and are very willing to help us. Yet I do sense some resentment to another research. Looks like these people have had researchers come here for a few years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a less serious, but equally important note: I have tried some hip things. Deep fried Mophane worms are one of them. They are a type of caterpillars that walk the Mophane trees. As well as sorghum porridge with sour milk. And some local (sorghum) beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also they have something called Magwinya. Very close to Afrikaans &amp;#8216;vetkoek&amp;#8217; and Dutch &amp;#8216;oliebollen&amp;#8217; (zonder krenten). Also I can now make phalitshe (pronounced as polidge), the name for the maize porridge. To try and fix your air-bed just as you do a flat on your bike is also a treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly you should know I have an awesome T-shirt tan by now :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Botlhale</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/13/botlhale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 10:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/13/botlhale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After being here 3 weeks (today is the start of my fourth week in the South), I thought it&amp;#8217;d be good to give another update. This week marks the start of my real &amp;#8216;field&amp;#8217; research. The previous two weeks of staying in Gaborone were weeks of article reading and enhancing (read: writing anew) my proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually I was planning to leave for Mopipi on Monday. However, there are always unexpected changes in this world. I&amp;#8217;m sorry to say that I found out yesterday that my interpreter/assistants grandmother has passed away. My sincere condolences to her family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a slight change in plans. This week I will still stay in Gaborone to start prepare all the data processing things and to process some satellite imagery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last post I said something about it be so extremely dry here. Well, things have changed. Monday last it started raining like crazy. Most unusual for winter. Moreover because it rained for 4 days. Luckily things have changed again. The sun is shining again and skies are blue. This a big relief, because staying in a house without central heating, can get cold at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently some people have been asking about what I&amp;#8217;m up to and what I&amp;#8217;m doing here. To relieve my beloved of these difficult and comprehensive questions there is a brief explanation on the link (above): &lt;a href=&#34;http://fritzvd.wordpress.com/research&#34;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Bothlale is Setswana for wisdom&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ga pula</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/03/ga-pula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 11:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/06/03/ga-pula/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thursday last I arrived in Gaborone, Botswana after a 7 hour busride through an extraordinary landscape, with shrubs, small trees and yellowish grass as far as the eye can see. A bouquet of dryland vegetation and rock formations passed us by. Beauty is something that is embedded into our wonderful planet earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaborone or Gabz is quite a new city. Don&amp;#8217;t expect old architecture like you see in Windhoek or Cape Town. Instead there are some malls. Of which the main mall is part of the older city centre, hence more fun to walk around in. It is actually only by name a mall, it&amp;#8217;s more a shopping boulevard, like you find in Amsterdam, only with a very thick African touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week or so staying with the Namibian Deputy High Commissioner, I can say that I could not have found more hospitable people to stay with. I have my own room and can borrow the car or ask for a ride whenever. Did not expect such luxury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The professor I was planning to meet on Monday was surprised to find me in Botswana so soon, when I called him on Friday. He expected me to be here in July. All is well, he stated: &amp;#8220;you are here now, so let&amp;#8217;s not waste time.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as my research is concerned, half of what I planned to do is going to be in vain. The Mopipi village area, is an area where people have already decided on an alternative energy source. They would like to use biogas. That basically means I have to re-write most of my proposal and change my research to find out what degradation processes might change due to a change to biogas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have to get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;But I am talking too much. It&amp;#8217;s because I chatter that I do nothing. Or perhaps it is that I chatter because I do nothing.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Dostoevsky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Ga pula is Setswana for: no rain. It&#39;s very dry here.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motoro</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/27/motoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 19:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/27/motoro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday I arrived in South Africa. The first thing I did after going through customs is renting a car. As lekker as it is to have my own mode of transportation, I struggled a bit with driving on the &amp;#8216;wrong&amp;#8217; side of the road. The first few drives were a bit shaky. After a while I got the hang of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day I went to Kempton Park to visit a friend of mine. After driving around for a bit I came at a dead end and figured I&amp;#8217;d better call him to make sure that I still know where he lives. Phone rang and I started driving again after stopping at the side of the road. Sarel picked up the phone as I realized that I was on the wrong side of the road. (Pardon my French for the following comment). &amp;#8220;F*ck! I&amp;#8217;m on the wrong side of the road!&amp;#8221; I cried out in panic/hysteria to Sarel, who on the other end of the line, could not stop laughing for the Dutchie cussing in the first hour he is in South Africa. This pandemonium was quickly resolved as I switched lanes to get on the left side of the road. No damage done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from this single and very rare event all the driving went fine. You just have get to get used to the heavy slopes when you stop and drive. I&amp;#8217;ve got the hang of the handbrake-stops now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will be leaving to go to Gaborone and staying with some of my father&amp;#8217;s friends (he knows people all over the place!). Monday I will be visiting the university for the first time. Let us hope the professors who I need to speak to are there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the right (not left!) of this post you can see some of the pictures I took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Motoro is Setswana for car (so I have been told)
Lekker is South African English for: lovely, nice, enjoyable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domela</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/07/domela/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 22:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/05/07/domela/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
  In the preparations for my trip, I find that slowly but gradually the stress, of the things needed to be done, starts to pile upon me. As for now I am trying to give my self a crash course in Setswana, the official language of the Batswana.&lt;br /&gt; But as with all things in life this is way harder than anticipated. Way harder. If I would like to say cup of coffee, it is not that difficult: kopi kofi (sounds a lot like the dutch). Yet if I want to borrow someones telephone, I can only say the word telephone. This is such a mouthful: mogola wa mosokela tsebeng. With just a cup of coffee I can come a long way.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
  To relieve some stress I have recorded some &lt;a title=&#34;music&#34; href=&#34;http://last.fm/music/Phritz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;songs&lt;/a&gt;. But sometimes this a days work, so I will have to refrain from doing so until I have finished writing my research proposal.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
  Some people have asked me what it is I am planning to do. The technical details are a bit boring. But I can give a hint of what I will be doing. The trip is part of my studies. In short I will show and promote other sources of energy. Maybe I can even try to showoff the solar cookers shown below.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
  Furthermore I will be venturing off into adventure. This is what I like most about this trip. I mean how often do we have the chance of going to Botswana?!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those interested, I will conduct a research concerning the use of fuelwood and the feasibility to switch to another, hopefully more renewable energy source. The use of fuelwood puts severe stress on the environment, and can cause further desertification (worsening and growing of a desert)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_16&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-16&#34; title=&#34;solarcookersillustration&#34; src=&#34;http://fritzvd.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/solarcookersillustration.gif?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;schematic&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;228&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    schematic
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_17&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-17&#34; title=&#34;fun-panel-las-image&#34; src=&#34;http://fritzvd.files.wordpress.com/2009/05/fun-panel-las-image.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;in use&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;237&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    in use
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Domela is Setswana for Hello.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>