<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artoolkit on fritzvd</title>
    <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/artoolkit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artoolkit on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:48:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/artoolkit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Random thoughts Augmented Reality</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/30/augmented-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/30/augmented-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another consideration is if using Augmented Reality (AR) how to implement it and what method of going about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARToolkit has different spin-offs that look quite interesting. One of my favourites are FLARToolkit and possibly SLARToolkit. The flash toolkit. But then I am not very proficient in Flash and ActionScript. Also I tend to avoid Flash as much as possible as well as writing stuff in C#. But the office I work in makes it easier to use C# then any other binding. Also there is a C# binding of OGRE which is quite well developed. OGRE is an opensource 3d gaming engine Which made me think: HTML5. Is there a solution for that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also OSGARToolkit looks interesting. It uses a well developed opensource C++ based 3d graphics toolkit OpenSceneGraph. Which itself has a GIS project going as well. (osggis and osgearth). A quite detailed and beautiful Flight Simulator &amp;#8211; FlightGear &amp;#8211; is also based on OSG. An interesting project based on the OSG library is Vizard. A library in Python (yey!) to create Virtual Environments. The only major drawback is that it costs a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some cool examples of FLARToolkit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://rawkes.com&#34;&gt;rawkes.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most viable of options seems to be the OSGARToolkit. It is free and above all it has quite good thorough documentation. To get started and to continue the work a bit. Just need to learn a bit of C++ (&lt;a href=&#34;http://lwn.net/Articles/249460/&#34;&gt;oh lord&lt;/a&gt;) and 3D modeling. This might be a long insomniac season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>