<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blabla on fritzvd</title>
    <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/blabla/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blabla on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 16:46:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/blabla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cape Town, flu and other frailties</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/09/12/cape-town-flu-and-other-frailties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 16:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/09/12/cape-town-flu-and-other-frailties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cape Town is freaking awesome. I realize this every time I wake up again. Last time I was here was in 2006 during DTS in Muizenberg. To be back here is nice. To hang out with Simon, Marieke and Noah is lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few days I have (with the help of anti-biotics) conquered flu, challenged Poseidon and battled the fierceness of the wrath of Simon and his axe. I have survived all, and still remain strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swimming in the ocean here, is like dipping your self in a bath of salty ice water with lots of current. Oh, how I love swimming in the sea. The last few times I went to the ocean, I could not curb my enthusiasm, but ripped of my clothes and jumped head first in to the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is of course a flipside to being in Cape Town. The contrast between the poorest and the richest is vast, and oftentimes just 500 meters apart. In a place of such a richness in beauty, surfing and mountain flora there is also a painful poverty. Adjacent to the souvenir shops a large township rises forth from the ground. It is a miracle that rich people can live here without a care. I blame it on a growing of calluses on the heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I will continue doing what I am doing. Chilling, hanging out and going into Ocean View (township) with Simon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>