<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tex on fritzvd</title>
    <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/tex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tex on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 08:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/tex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the Dots</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2011/02/28/connecting-the-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 08:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2011/02/28/connecting-the-dots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who think they &amp;#8220;know&amp;#8221; everything from the beginning will never, in fact, come to know anything &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;Thomas Merton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks (months) I haven&amp;#8217;t been posting too much. Sorry about that. For all the people who are interested in what I am doing a little update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment I am trying to write up the document to present the thesis to my supervisors. The research part is almost brought to an end with this step. Then the big question is, what are my findings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t quite distilled that to a complete concrete conclusion, but I can say this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3D GIS is not an easy thing. Depending on the quality of the 3D visualization of course. But trying to get the coordinate systems of a Geographical System to work together with 3D software and their coordinate systems is not an easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An instance of Augmented Reality is only as good as the purposes it should serve and the requirements it should fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, LaTeX is an awesome markup tool for word processing. If someone is interested in the title page for a thesis at the WUR (Wageningen University and Research) just comment and I&amp;#8217;ll send you the .tex file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Monday!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>