<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>minor-thesis on fritzvd</title>
    <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/categories/minor-thesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in minor-thesis on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 08:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.fritzvd.com/categories/minor-thesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the Dots</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2011/02/28/connecting-the-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 08:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2011/02/28/connecting-the-dots/</guid>
      <description>Those who think they “know” everything from the beginning will never, in fact, come to know anything – Thomas Merton
Over the last few weeks (months) I haven’t been posting too much. Sorry about that. For all the people who are interested in what I am doing a little update.
At the moment I am trying to write up the document to present the thesis to my supervisors. The research part is almost brought to an end with this step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From 2.5D to 3D</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2011/01/10/from-2-5d-to-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 14:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2011/01/10/from-2-5d-to-3d/</guid>
      <description>My last few posts have focused on somewhat other things than my thesis. This does not mean that no progress has been made or that I’ve done nothing. On the contrary; I’ve done quite a bit. But it is rather less exciting.
I’ve been busy with data conversion and trying to get a working 3D representation that is meaningful. Which is hard and not so spectacular. Seriously. First of all getting to grips with the fact that the reason why ESRI is marketleader may be because they deliver a complete and good package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three I&amp;#8217;s of progress.</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/12/17/interaction-interfacing-iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 15:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/12/17/interaction-interfacing-iteration/</guid>
      <description>In my little project I would like to add some _I_nteraction. A possibility to zoom in and out and rotate the 3D model without moving the marker but by using some form of hand gestures. This should be possible. Though, the road towards it still seems a bit unclear.
For now I have investigated the possibility of loading the 3D model as a static object until other markers arrive on the scene and are able to manipulate position, rotation and zooming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popular Demand</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/12/17/popular-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 10:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/12/17/popular-demand/</guid>
      <description>You can witness the magic happen on your very own desk, if you’d like. Print out the marker and allow Flash to access your webcam.
Click here to watch the magic happen.
If you do not know how to allow Flash to access your webcam Follow the instructions below
Right click in the black window that opens and select “Settings” Click on “allow” like displayed in the little image below Let the awesomeness overwhelm you like the wondrous fragrance of Lavender on a spring day P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whoops I FLARted..</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/12/08/222/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 18:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/12/08/222/</guid>
      <description>Today I fooled around a bit with the FLARManager (tutorials graciously provided by transmote). I tried to get some Papervision 3D objects going using all these different tutorials I have been following over the last few weeks (e.g. papervision2.com and rawkes.com). But it has not been as easy as I had expected. But then again, things never are.
The difficulty is not so much in displaying 3D objects, because pv3d and flarmanager do all the thinking for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendered Useless</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/11/30/rendered-useless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 17:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/11/30/rendered-useless/</guid>
      <description>A little update on what I am doing. Today is a pictureless day, too bad.
Moving away from Mayavi2 I have been moving towards ActionScript and Flash. Why this switch? Well Mayavi2 is a real cool scientific visualization tool, but most of the focus is on on-the-fly visualization of data that is dense, but also a computer that is powerful. This does not really serve useful for the purposes I would want to move towards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing images with GDAL and Mayavi2</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/11/22/processing-images-with-gdal-and-mayavi2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 12:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/11/22/processing-images-with-gdal-and-mayavi2/</guid>
      <description>Ok, this took a while but the results are not bad. So I guess it’s worth it.
First of all, a big thank you at [Ok, this took a while but the results are not bad. So I guess it’s worth it.
First of all, a big thank you at](http://www.gis.usu.edu/~chrisg/) who is very possibly unaware of the fact that I have been using his classes on Python and Open Source GIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developments so far</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/11/18/developments-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 15:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/11/18/developments-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Ok. 3 weeks down the road of my minor thesis and what do I have to show for? Well, a lot of paradigms and concepts for starters. Furthermore I have never been able to finish a document like research proposal so quickly and of such quality.
But enough of that. I have more or less abandoned the idea of a mobile application for now. Because having a mobile application like Junaio scores high on the cool list, it doesn’t really in the sphere of performance and handling large data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Directions</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/10/02/different-directions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 17:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/10/02/different-directions/</guid>
      <description>It seems that my minor thesis will focus more on the user experience of augmented reality. The EIA’s have raster outputs that can be converted to 3D spaces. These spaces can then be given Locations. The Raster is already georeferenced which would make this easier (I think).
The best method of viewing these things would seem Augmented Reality browsers such as Layar or Junaio. So I would have to brush up a bit on what is possible in which browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random thoughts Augmented Reality</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/30/augmented-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/30/augmented-reality/</guid>
      <description>Another consideration is if using Augmented Reality (AR) how to implement it and what method of going about it.
ARToolkit has different spin-offs that look quite interesting. One of my favourites are FLARToolkit and possibly SLARToolkit. The flash toolkit. But then I am not very proficient in Flash and ActionScript. Also I tend to avoid Flash as much as possible as well as writing stuff in C#. But the office I work in makes it easier to use C# then any other binding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations on which Gaming Engine to use</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/29/considerations-on-which-gaming-engine-to-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 15:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/29/considerations-on-which-gaming-engine-to-use/</guid>
      <description>A quick update on my project of using a Gaming Engine to process GIS data. After some googling and reading other peoples blogs and workspaces it seems that some engines are more fit than others.
Tim Germanchis et al. (2005) has done a brief overview of different game engines for this particular usage. Amongst which are the Quake III, Unreal Runtime 2, CryEngine and others. The CryEngine apparently suited the writer the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability and 3D in Geovisualization</title>
      <link>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/29/considerations-on-3d-visualization-for-gis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 14:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fritzvd.com/2010/09/29/considerations-on-3d-visualization-for-gis/</guid>
      <description>For my minor thesis I am thinking of a project for processing Environmental Impact Assessment in a way that is more easily comprehensible. For this project I intend to use Augmented Reality. Hopefully some form of 3d visualization. And I am looking at the possibilities of using gaming engines.
First and foremost, this is a preliminary research. I am not in any way an expert. And only just learning about the amazing possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
