<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Open Source on fritzvd</title>
    <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/open-open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Open Source on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 11:37:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/open-open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>OPEN Open Source</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2014/09/15/open-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 11:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2014/09/15/open-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals making significant and valuable contributions are given commit-access to the project to contribute as they see fit. This project is more like an open wiki than a standard guarded open source project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rules&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a few basic ground-rules for contributors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No &amp;#8211;force pushes or modifying the Git history in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-master branches ought to be used for ongoing work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External API changes and significant modifications ought to be subject to an internal pull-request to solicit feedback from other contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal pull-requests to solicit feedback are encouraged for any other non-trivial contribution but left to the discretion of the contributor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributors should attempt to adhere to the prevailing code-style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Releases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declaring formal releases remains the prerogative of the project maintainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes to this arrangement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an experiment and feedback is welcome! This document may also be subject to pull requests or changes by contributors where you believe you have something valuable to add or change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Rod Vagg and the LevelUP project for coming up with the idea of &amp;#8220;OPEN Open Source&amp;#8221;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rvagg/node-levelup/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34; title=&#34;webtorrent contributing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;node-levelup&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s contributing page)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>