<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>serial on fritzvd</title>
    <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/tags/serial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in serial on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fritzvd.com/blog/tags/serial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Chopping Board</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/02/14/The-Chopping-Board/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/02/14/The-Chopping-Board/</guid>
      <description>It was a strange and extremely warm summer afternoon. The kind of warmth that strangles you like a psychopath but also makes you feel a one-ness with the world. One of those evenings where it is hard to know where the body stops and the atmosphere begins. Where sweat drops don&amp;rsquo;t chill the body, and where everything blurs.
One man who was not entirely enjoying this was standing outside, bent over to grab his lighter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night of Grafting - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/01/08/Night-of-Grafting-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 14:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/01/08/Night-of-Grafting-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>That first night, now felt like it must have been years ago, Shan thought to himself, even if it was only 2 weeks. Besides the fatigue of climbing that first day it was not a very taxing day. Not like the others. It was the other nights that kept him brooding. The other nights where they had to go without food. Where they felt haunted by restless dreams. Where he could not be sure that what he saw was actually there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night of Grafting - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2017/12/22/Night-of-Grafting-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 19:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2017/12/22/Night-of-Grafting-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>It was dark and cold, and the morning never seemed to come, to Shan. He was never one for being impatient, but tonight was different. Sleep did usually come quickly for Shan of Bomul. But tonight was different. Not only was he unable to catch sleep because he kept brooding; tonight also marked his last in many ways. Since Shan, Inzil of Limir and Mago of Fer, left home a fortnight ago they had no idea what kind of time this would be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
