<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>story on fritzvd</title>
    <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/tags/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in story on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 06:49:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fritzvd.com/blog/tags/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wild Ride</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2020/03/10/Wild-Ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 06:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2020/03/10/Wild-Ride/</guid>
      <description>Myrtl and Hog jumped down the chute, with Myrtl crying out in sheer revelry: &amp;ldquo;Whoo-hoo&amp;rdquo;. They had been going about this for months on end now and the thrill had not diminished as of yet. The hustle and bustle of the city combined with the rush of being chased, it was just too good to be true.
After the garbage chute there would be one more challenge before losing in on their home: the bus station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jakob’s ice cream</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2019/08/11/Jakobs-ice-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 21:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2019/08/11/Jakobs-ice-cream/</guid>
      <description>“I’ll stab you square between your eyes, vile scorpion blooded motherfucker”, Jakob shouted at the olid man standing right in front of him. His undersized yellow stained tank top wasn’t very becoming, neither was the sweat that was dripping down his armpit hair. The stench was atrocious and hardly bearable.
Of course Jakob was a coward and never really shouted. He just stood there thinking all these wonderful thoughts.
The day had started so great in te suburban cement ridden shithole that was his hometown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chopping Board</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/02/14/The-Chopping-Board/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/02/14/The-Chopping-Board/</guid>
      <description>It was a strange and extremely warm summer afternoon. The kind of warmth that strangles you like a psychopath but also makes you feel a one-ness with the world. One of those evenings where it is hard to know where the body stops and the atmosphere begins. Where sweat drops don&amp;rsquo;t chill the body, and where everything blurs.
One man who was not entirely enjoying this was standing outside, bent over to grab his lighter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mountain</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/02/09/The-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 14:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/02/09/The-mountain/</guid>
      <description>The mountain was on fire. The clouds above it, light, cumulous clouds drawn up by the daily winds, drawn from the montane forests covered in fog, drawn out of the green fields beneath the mountain, were bathed in a golden, red light from the setting sun. The sea in front of the mountain scintillated and shimmered, drew out the static sunset and cast it in a thousand gems on the surface of the water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Violin</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/01/31/The-Second-Violin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 12:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/01/31/The-Second-Violin/</guid>
      <description>It was a long drive home, it always was. It&amp;rsquo;s always a longer drive than anyone ever hoped. No drive is really is short enough after 2 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning. Last time she drove this way home it was with Craig right beside her. He&amp;rsquo;d been playing third that evening. Suzie had played second violin. As she had done for a few years now. Back then, she was new to the gig and Craig always liked driving together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night of Grafting - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/01/08/Night-of-Grafting-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 14:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2018/01/08/Night-of-Grafting-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>That first night, now felt like it must have been years ago, Shan thought to himself, even if it was only 2 weeks. Besides the fatigue of climbing that first day it was not a very taxing day. Not like the others. It was the other nights that kept him brooding. The other nights where they had to go without food. Where they felt haunted by restless dreams. Where he could not be sure that what he saw was actually there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night of Grafting - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2017/12/22/Night-of-Grafting-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 19:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2017/12/22/Night-of-Grafting-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>It was dark and cold, and the morning never seemed to come, to Shan. He was never one for being impatient, but tonight was different. Sleep did usually come quickly for Shan of Bomul. But tonight was different. Not only was he unable to catch sleep because he kept brooding; tonight also marked his last in many ways. Since Shan, Inzil of Limir and Mago of Fer, left home a fortnight ago they had no idea what kind of time this would be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
