<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travels on fritzvd</title>
    <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/travels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travels on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 09:41:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.fritzvd.com/tags/travels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>jumping borders</title>
      <link>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/09/02/jumping-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 09:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.fritzvd.com/2009/09/02/jumping-borders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I arrived safely at Cape Town Int. Airport. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simonandmarieke.com&#34;&gt;Simon, Marieke and Noah&lt;/a&gt; came to pick me up. A bit surreal to see them, but very good nonetheless. Surreal because I have seen so many places in quite a short amount of time over the last few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I posted something on my blog, I did so from the town of Victoria Falls in the North-West of Zimbabwe. After posting we went to see the world famous Falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they are astounding. What an awesome, tremendous display of power and majesty that is. Roaring like a lion does a herd of wild waters rush down the steep ridges. Rush down and come back up again, come back up again in victorious mist that shatters sunlight into a million pieces. A rainbow so bright that it does not seem to be real. A sight so violent that it seems unlikely to bring life wherever the water flows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Vic Falls, we hitchhiked back to Bulawayo, this time a free ride in a nice Land Cruiser. In Bulawayo we spent another 2 days before I travelled back to Johannesburg. That was quite a crazy experience. Although I chose a well trusted company: Greyhound, the bus driver took more passengers than allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other special thing, the border post. You have never seen queues like you have seen them at the Zimbabwean-South African border post. We stood in a queue literally reaching up to at least 150 m. (I shot a little film clip that I will upload somewhere in the near future). Furthermore we spent 4 hours crossing the border before we could continue driving to Johannesburg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for now, I am in Cape Town. Enjoying and loving the time I have with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simonandmarieke.com&#34;&gt;Simon Marieke and Noah&lt;/a&gt;. Over the next three weeks I will just be hanging out with friends and wha-evs. For new phone number see contact page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>