<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on fritzvd</title>
    <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/categories/Uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 21:12:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fritzvd.com/blog/categories/Uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jakob’s ice cream</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2019/08/11/Jakobs-ice-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 21:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2019/08/11/Jakobs-ice-cream/</guid>
      <description>“I’ll stab you square between your eyes, vile scorpion blooded motherfucker”, Jakob shouted at the olid man standing right in front of him. His undersized yellow stained tank top wasn’t very becoming, neither was the sweat that was dripping down his armpit hair. The stench was atrocious and hardly bearable.
Of course Jakob was a coward and never really shouted. He just stood there thinking all these wonderful thoughts.
The day had started so great in te suburban cement ridden shithole that was his hometown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Tests for NativeScript apps</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2015/10/13/writing-tests-for-nativescript-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 06:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2015/10/13/writing-tests-for-nativescript-apps/</guid>
      <description>This has been bugging me for a while. While working on my business logic and REST API connection in my NativeScript project, I couldn’t write tests because requiring the tns-core-modules broke the test.
NativeScript is a library with tooling to create iOS and Android apps in JavaScript. And it works smoothly. However at the moment the docs aren’t always complete. Anyways, building and deploying an app on a mobile device (or emulator) takes somewhere in the range of a minute or so on a fast machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Documentation @ nodeconf 2015</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2015/07/01/writing-documentation-nodeconf-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 08:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2015/07/01/writing-documentation-nodeconf-2015/</guid>
      <description>This topic of course ties in with the Building Communities session. Because building community happens with code that is being used. And if you want people to be able to join easily, one of their first entry points will probably be the README, which has for some projects become the only or the main documentation.
At the moment the documentation of some projects is exemplary (think: anything @substack makes). Whereas the documentation of node itself is kind of a mess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2012/02/04/snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2012/02/04/snow/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2010</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2011/01/01/my-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 14:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2011/01/01/my-2010/</guid>
      <description>
All in all not a bad year, I would say. Just a quick overview of some highlights and the soundtrack of the last year.
The Good
Engaged to Nelleke Bachelor of Science Started a business Royal Haskoning Rock Climbing! / Spain Trip the Harry Potter Septology Spotify! Water Insight Android Vienna Pablo Picasso’s violin Mac Mini Beatles Discography Reading, reading reading. Met awesome people. Etc. The Soundtrack
Jakob Dylan – Women + Country Everything Everything – Man Alive Mumford &amp;amp; Sons – Sigh No More Vampire Weekend – Contra Cyndi Lauper – Memphis Blues MGMT – Congratulations Ray LaMontagne And The Pariah Dogs – God Willin’ &amp;amp; The Creek Don’t Rise The Black Keys – Brothers Kings of Leon – Come Around Sundown Brown Feather Sparrow – How to Throw a Christmas Party </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of God</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/12/24/in-search-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 14:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/12/24/in-search-of-god/</guid>
      <description>Tuning into a TV program sporting The Face – Kings of Leon last week got me thinking. The program is called In Search of God and features 3 Dutch Celeb’s which are facilitated with a number of conversations and travels that should help them find God. Or at least give a nudge in that general direction or other.
I found the program to be most intriguing and turns out to probably be my favorite show of the year (next to the Big C, which is also deserves a great mention here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I still refuse to cook electric and why we should finish natural resources</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/09/10/why-i-still-refuse-to-cook-electric-and-why-we-should-finish-natural-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 12:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/09/10/why-i-still-refuse-to-cook-electric-and-why-we-should-finish-natural-resources/</guid>
      <description>Today I had quite an epiphany while I was working the oven (a gas oven that is). I love gas. It is by far the best way to cook. Electric cooking has always seemed a bit gay to me. And I know usually gays are quite advanced and up to speed with fads and ins and outs. But I thoroughly believe that they are wrong on this account.
Electric cooking always requires you to think ahead whilst you are cooking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death or freedom of it&amp;#039;s sting</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/02/23/death-or-freedom-of-its-sting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 23:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/02/23/death-or-freedom-of-its-sting/</guid>
      <description>Today, after a long time of keyboard-silence, I return with a cheerful blog post on death. Why? Well, yesterday my grandfather passed away, which reminds us of our last foe. He was a (war)hero, at least to me he was.
Strangely enough I stumbled upon Johnny Cash album: VI – Ain’t No Grave only an hour after hearing the sad news. This is a beautiful recording of someone who wasn’t afraid of death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>overcoming the incomprehensible</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/12/24/overcoming-the-incomprehensible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 12:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/12/24/overcoming-the-incomprehensible/</guid>
      <description>Some things lie outside our command, some things outside our understanding. Or better yet, only some things lie in our command and understanding. Our eyes are limited, and our mind even more so. We see things that are not there, do not see things that might be there, speculate about how events take place in the (Super)Natural world. And all the while we think a real big deal of ourselves, whilst forgetting that we are very tiny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>general frustrations on nobel-prize winning presidents</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/10/21/general-frustrations-on-nobel-prize-winning-presidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 11:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/10/21/general-frustrations-on-nobel-prize-winning-presidents/</guid>
      <description>There is something which has been lingering in my mind for a while now. It has been brooding one US president ago, and has been set to full throttle frustration when a nobel prize was awarded a week-and-some ago.
US presidents have always, in the good-spirited leadership they posses, urged other ‘fragile states’ that nuclear power is something that comes with great responsibility, just like spidey-senses. And of course fragile states cannot handle that kind of responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google 4th to appear on Google</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/10/08/google-4th-to-appear-on-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 14:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/10/08/google-4th-to-appear-on-google/</guid>
      <description>When writing a thesis, it is imperative that you lose focus every now and then. So after reading some blogs, during the lunch-break, I decided to extend my lunch break. Little did I know I was destined to find out something extraordinary.
When you try to find a search engine in Google, Google is the 5th result, (4th webpage) you’ll find.
This of course is groundbreaking research in the field of Desertification and Development Sociology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>unity in diversity</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/09/30/unity-in-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 17:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/09/30/unity-in-diversity/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I will be leaving South Africa to fly to the Netherlands. It has been good, but it is also time to go back. But before I go and before I close this blog down (or start posting non-interesting thoughts on how to design your own vegetable garden), I want to leave you with an impression of the country of my forefathers. The beautiful, complex and diverse South Africa whom I have grown to love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cape Town, flu and other frailties</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/09/12/cape-town-flu-and-other-frailties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 16:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/09/12/cape-town-flu-and-other-frailties/</guid>
      <description>Cape Town is freaking awesome. I realize this every time I wake up again. Last time I was here was in 2006 during DTS in Muizenberg. To be back here is nice. To hang out with Simon, Marieke and Noah is lovely.
Over the last few days I have (with the help of anti-biotics) conquered flu, challenged Poseidon and battled the fierceness of the wrath of Simon and his axe. I have survived all, and still remain strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jumping borders</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/09/02/jumping-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 09:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/09/02/jumping-borders/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I arrived safely at Cape Town Int. Airport. Simon, Marieke and Noah came to pick me up. A bit surreal to see them, but very good nonetheless. Surreal because I have seen so many places in quite a short amount of time over the last few days.
Last time I posted something on my blog, I did so from the town of Victoria Falls in the North-West of Zimbabwe. After posting we went to see the world famous Falls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/04/19/going/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 23:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2009/04/19/going/</guid>
      <description>I am actually going. And not long from now. This blog will keep you updated on my happy adventures in Southern Africa over the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
