<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3dgis on fritzvd</title>
    <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/tags/3dgis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3dgis on fritzvd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 08:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fritzvd.com/blog/tags/3dgis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the Dots</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2011/02/28/connecting-the-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 08:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2011/02/28/connecting-the-dots/</guid>
      <description>Those who think they “know” everything from the beginning will never, in fact, come to know anything – Thomas Merton
Over the last few weeks (months) I haven’t been posting too much. Sorry about that. For all the people who are interested in what I am doing a little update.
At the moment I am trying to write up the document to present the thesis to my supervisors. The research part is almost brought to an end with this step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From 2.5D to 3D</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2011/01/10/from-2-5d-to-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 14:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2011/01/10/from-2-5d-to-3d/</guid>
      <description>My last few posts have focused on somewhat other things than my thesis. This does not mean that no progress has been made or that I’ve done nothing. On the contrary; I’ve done quite a bit. But it is rather less exciting.
I’ve been busy with data conversion and trying to get a working 3D representation that is meaningful. Which is hard and not so spectacular. Seriously. First of all getting to grips with the fact that the reason why ESRI is marketleader may be because they deliver a complete and good package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on LiDAR</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/12/02/thoughts-on-lidar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 15:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/12/02/thoughts-on-lidar/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was fortunate enough to be able to visit the European LiDAR Mapping Forum (ELMF) in The Hague. For those who do not know what LiDAR is, it is a sensor that acquires high-quality (very dense) 3D data. If you would like to check out some of the data, what it looks like and play around with it a bit, here is a “get-started”. It is further explained on Wikipedia, to which you should give some money for using it on a daily basis, if you haven’t done so already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing images with GDAL and Mayavi2</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/11/22/processing-images-with-gdal-and-mayavi2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 12:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/11/22/processing-images-with-gdal-and-mayavi2/</guid>
      <description>Ok, this took a while but the results are not bad. So I guess it’s worth it.
First of all, a big thank you at [Ok, this took a while but the results are not bad. So I guess it’s worth it.
First of all, a big thank you at](http://www.gis.usu.edu/~chrisg/) who is very possibly unaware of the fact that I have been using his classes on Python and Open Source GIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developments so far</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/11/18/developments-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 15:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/11/18/developments-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Ok. 3 weeks down the road of my minor thesis and what do I have to show for? Well, a lot of paradigms and concepts for starters. Furthermore I have never been able to finish a document like research proposal so quickly and of such quality.
But enough of that. I have more or less abandoned the idea of a mobile application for now. Because having a mobile application like Junaio scores high on the cool list, it doesn’t really in the sphere of performance and handling large data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Directions</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/10/02/different-directions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 17:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/10/02/different-directions/</guid>
      <description>It seems that my minor thesis will focus more on the user experience of augmented reality. The EIA’s have raster outputs that can be converted to 3D spaces. These spaces can then be given Locations. The Raster is already georeferenced which would make this easier (I think).
The best method of viewing these things would seem Augmented Reality browsers such as Layar or Junaio. So I would have to brush up a bit on what is possible in which browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations on which Gaming Engine to use</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/09/29/considerations-on-which-gaming-engine-to-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 15:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/09/29/considerations-on-which-gaming-engine-to-use/</guid>
      <description>A quick update on my project of using a Gaming Engine to process GIS data. After some googling and reading other peoples blogs and workspaces it seems that some engines are more fit than others.
Tim Germanchis et al. (2005) has done a brief overview of different game engines for this particular usage. Amongst which are the Quake III, Unreal Runtime 2, CryEngine and others. The CryEngine apparently suited the writer the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability and 3D in Geovisualization</title>
      <link>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/09/29/considerations-on-3d-visualization-for-gis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 14:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fritzvd.com/blog/2010/09/29/considerations-on-3d-visualization-for-gis/</guid>
      <description>For my minor thesis I am thinking of a project for processing Environmental Impact Assessment in a way that is more easily comprehensible. For this project I intend to use Augmented Reality. Hopefully some form of 3d visualization. And I am looking at the possibilities of using gaming engines.
First and foremost, this is a preliminary research. I am not in any way an expert. And only just learning about the amazing possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
